<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Case-studies on NumPy</title>
    <link>http://numpy.org/case-studies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Case-studies on NumPy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="http://numpy.org/case-studies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: Cricket Analytics, the game changer!</title>
      <link>http://numpy.org/case-studies/cricket-analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://numpy.org/case-studies/cricket-analytics/</guid>
      <description>IPLT20, the biggest Cricket Festival in India (Image credits: IPLT20 (cup and logo) &amp;amp; Akash Yadav (stadium))
  You don&#39;t play for the crowd, you play for the country.
—M S Dhoni, International Cricket Player, ex-captain, Indian Team, plays for Chennai Super Kings in IPL  About Cricket It would be an understatement to state that Indians love cricket. The game is played in just about every nook and cranny of India, rural or urban, popular with the young and the old alike, connecting billions in India unlike any other sport.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: DeepLabCut 3D Pose Estimation</title>
      <link>http://numpy.org/case-studies/deeplabcut-dnn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://numpy.org/case-studies/deeplabcut-dnn/</guid>
      <description>Analyzing mice hand-movement using DeepLapCut (Source: www.deeplabcut.org )
  Open Source Software is accelerating Biomedicine. DeepLabCut enables automated video analysis of animal behavior using Deep Learning.
—Alexander Mathis, Assistant Professor, École polytechnique fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL)  About DeepLabCut DeepLabCut is an open source toolbox that empowers researchers at hundreds of institutions worldwide to track behaviour of laboratory animals, with very little training data, at human-level accuracy. With DeepLabCut technology, scientists can delve deeper into the scientific understanding of motor control and behavior across animal species and timescales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: Discovery of Gravitational Waves</title>
      <link>http://numpy.org/case-studies/gw-discov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://numpy.org/case-studies/gw-discov/</guid>
      <description>Gravitational Waves (Image Credits: The Simulating eXtreme Spacetimes (SXS) Project at LIGO)
  The scientific Python ecosystem is critical infrastructure for the research done at LIGO.
David Shoemaker, LIGO Scientific Collaboration  About Gravitational Waves and LIGO Gravitational waves are ripples in the fabric of space and time, generated by cataclysmic events in the universe such as collision and merging of two black holes or coalescing binary stars or supernovae.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Case Study: First Image of a Black Hole</title>
      <link>http://numpy.org/case-studies/blackhole-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://numpy.org/case-studies/blackhole-image/</guid>
      <description>Black Hole M87 (Image Credits: Event Horizon Telescope Collaboration)
  Imaging the M87 Black Hole is like trying to see something that is by definition impossible to see.
Katie Bouman, Assistant Professor, Computing &amp; Mathematical Sciences, Caltech  A telescope the size of the earth The Event Horizon telescope (EHT) is an array of eight ground-based radio telescopes forming a computational telescope the size of the earth, studing the universe with unprecedented sensitivity and resolution.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>